Lessons five.
Adding and formatting table to your presentation.
Tables in presentation is needed for some numerical data purposes and organizing texts by the use of rows and columns.
Objectives
to create and formatting a simple table that can be use to your powerpoint presentation.
Topic A: Creating a table.
A table is a grid of cells arranged in rows and columns.
To create the table
first look for to insert tab in toolbar.
Then click table icon.
And this will appear.
As you can see here.
this number indicates how many columns and rows you wish to put to your slide.
Four columns and four rows, yellow arrow for columns and red arrow for rows.
After selecting columns and rows for your table.
This bar will appear.
Here
you can select different colors for a table that you would like to use.
Now click this button here.
And this will appear
with different variants of colors for your tables.
You can always decide which color would you like to use for your table.
That's it for creating a table.
Topic B: Formatting a table.
Click at the space on the top left the table, and begin typing to add text.
Let’s put sample an text.
Input family, name, age and favorite color.
Just like this.
Now let’s try to input the needed data in each column like family member, name, their age, and favorite color like this.
Now if you like to add columns and rows click anywhere in the table.
And this layout tab will appear.
Then click it.
This bar will show you the row and column groups
here you can add column and row you wish to add to your table.
Let me show you how.
If you wish to add row above the first row
first you need to navigate the cursor of your mouse to the first row and click it.
Like this.
Next by clicking insert above, the new row will appear above
like this
And if you like to add row below the family, name, age and favorite color.
Click insert below and it will look like this.
But if you wish to add new row below the sister text, navigate your cursor of your mouse and click the sister text
like this.
Then click the insert below to add new row below
That's all for adding row.
You can always decide where to put rules by navigating and clicking a row.
Whether you want to add new at the top or below.
Next let's add columns.
By navigating your cursor of your mouse through the texts, you can decide where to put or to add columns.
For example let's add the column on the left side of the family column.
click insert left like this, and this is how it would look like.
Next let's put a new column in the middle of family and name column.
Drag or navigate your cursor on the texts and click that text.
For now let's click and between the family and name column.
Click insert right and this is what it should look like.
Now let’s add new column in the right side of the favorite color column
Navigate your cursor and click the favorite color of text.
Next click insert right.
Now it should look like this.
And that’s it for creating and formatting a table in powerpoint presentation
Good job
Now you know how to create and format a table for powerpoint presentation.
Activity for lessons five.
Now that you have an idea on how to create and format a table in powerpoint.
Let's now try this activity.
Now let’s create a table for addition.
First all you need to do is insert a table.
We're going to need two columns and eleven rows.
Two columns for the title operation and score label.
And eleven rows for the title bar and items of ten.
Click table bar in insert tab
Since the maximum is just compose of eight rows.
Find the layout tab and add two rows by clicking insert below three times.
Now it has eleven rows and two columns.
Now let’s input simple addition table like this.
That’s all for the activity for lesson five
Adding and Formatting table to your presentation.