Lesson two.
Developing a powerpoint presentation.
Hello there.
Welcome to lesson two.
In this video you will be learning how to use clipboards
font formatting tools and different presentation slides.
Objectives.
You will learn how to use the clipboard and font formatting tools.
You will learn different types of powerpoint slide.
First let's start by opening your Microsoft powerpoint then create a blank presentation
by clicking here.
Very good.
You have created yourself a blank presentation page.
A title slide will appear on your screen.
Now let's click the title box that says click to add title.
To add a title on your slide
let's type planets on your keyboard
Planets.
Under the little box is the subtitle box that says click to add subtitle.
To add subtitles on your title slide.
Type your full name and press enter. then type your grade level under your full name.
Let's change the font style and size of the word planets in the title box
to do it
click here and you can see that there are many font styles on the list.
Let's choose this Algerian font style.
Now let's change the size of the word planets by clicking here.
You can see that there are many font size us on the list.
Let's choose the biggest size here which is ninety six.
Good job.
Let's move to the subtitle box
highlight your name and grade inside the subtitle the box.
Do you still remember how to highlight?
To highlight a text.
You need to hold the left click off your mouse and drag
be moving your mouse pointer from the words you want to highlight.
Now let's highlight your name and your grade.
If you want to make your text bigger.
Click this button
and the text will go bigger and if you like this button.
That text will go smaller.
Great job.
Now let's continue and create a new slide
click here to create a new slide.
There are many types of slides.
This is the title slide.
It's the first slide that you see when you start a presentation.
this is the title and content slide.
This is the section section header slide.
This is the two content slide.
This is the comparison slide.
This is the title only slide.
This is the blank slide
this is the content and with captions slide.
This is the picture with caption slide
Let's choose the title and content slide.
Inside the text box of the title box
type planets.
Do you see font section over here.
It has a lot of formatting tools that will help you to style your text
Now let's explore different font formatting tools in powerpoint.
This is the Bold button.
This makes your text looked like this.
This is the Italic button.
This makes your text look like this.
This is the Underline button.
This is the Shadow button.
This makes your text look like this.
This is the Strike Through button.
Now you know how the different font button works.
Let's bold and underlined the text
planets.
Then let's color the text green and to do that click this button.
You can choose many colors you want but let's choose this color green here.
Great job.
Now that you learn the basics of font formatting tools and how to color a text.
Let's move to clipboard.
Do you know what the clipboard is?
This is a clipboard.
It has four useful parts that helps us
to copy
paste
cut
and the format painter.
Now let's try to copy the text.
Planet
than paste it in this text box
First highlight the text planet.
To do it.
Hold the left click off your mouse and dragged the words inside of the text box.
To copy the text you highlight click this button and it will now copy your text.
to paste the text you copied. click this button and it will now place your text in the textbox.
click this button and it will now place your text in the textbox.
To remove it. click this button and the text is now gone.
If you paste a lot of text in the text box. And you want the erase the other copies.
You can highlight the text you want to remove then click the cut obutton.
The text you highlighted will be removed from the textbox.
Good job
Now you know how to use a clipboard properly.
Now let's move onto the character spacing formats.
Do you know what the character spacing format is?
Character spacing is the amount of space between the characters within the line.
Characters are letters numbers and symbols.
This is the Very Tight spacing.
The spacing on each character is very close to each other.
This is the Tight spacing
the spacing of each character is close to each other.
This is the Normal spacing
the spacing of each character it's not too close or not too far to each other.
This is the Loose spacing.
This spacing of each character is a litle far from each other.
This is the Very Loose spacing.
This spacing of each character is very far from each other.
Let's talk about letter case formats.
Lettert case format changes the letters into small and big letters
it also changes the arrangement of letters too.
This is the sentence case
this only makes your first letter big
this is the lower case.
This makes all your letter small.
This is the upper case.
This makes all your letters big
this is the capitalized case.
This makes all the first letters big on each word.
This is the toggle case.
This makes all the big letters smaller while all the small letters are bigger.
Congratulations.
Now you know how to create a simple powerpoint presentation.
In the next video
you will be learning how to add graphical elements your presentation.
Activity for lesson two.
Hello there.
Now you know the basic font formatting paragraph formatting
and the different types of slides in powerpoint.
Let's try and test what you have learned from our lesson.
Do you know about planets?
Today let's explore different planets we have in our solar system.
Let's start by choosing the title only slide and type planets inside of the textbox.
To do it.
click this button and choose this slide then click this text box then type
planets.
Wonderful
but the title is too small.
Let's make it bigger and the that should be in bold.
To do it
let's highlight first the text then go to the fonts section and click this bold button.
Now let's click this font size button to make the text bigger
and let's choose thirty six for the font size.
Great
Now that title is big and it's in bold.
Let's choose another slide by going to the slides section again by clicking this button
and choose two content slides.
In the title section you need to type "types of planets"
inside the textbox of the two content slide on the left content section
name at least three planets you know.
And each planet you should change their font. Font styles and font color.
To do it
click this text box in the title section.
And type "types of planets" and the text box of the left content section.
Let's type the three planets you know which are the Earth, Mars, and Venus
now
let's highlight the earth and change the font to Arial.
Click this font button then pick the Arial font.
Now the earth's font are in Arial now.
For Mars.
Let's highlight it and then change the font styles to underline by clicking this button.
The font style of mars you can see is already underlined.
The last planet was Venus.
Let's change the font color of it by going to the font section again
and click this font color button and change it into blue.
Well done
you did a great job
for the last part.
On the right content section.
Type this planet's name.
In the text box which are Saturn, Jupiter, Mercury, and Neptune.
And you need to change the lettter case and characters spacing of the planets
to do it
if you want to set Saturn's to small letters.
Then go to the letter case button and choose lowercase.
This big letters from Saturn will turn into small letters.
for Jupiter
Go to the letter case button and and choose upper case.
This big letters from Jupiter will turn into big letters
if you want to change the spacing of Mercury text.
Into the very tight.
Highlight Mercury then go to the characters spacing button then click very tight.
The Mercury text spacing is very close to each other.
For Neptune
if you want to change the spacing of Neptune text into very loose.
Highlight Neptune. Then go to the character spacing button then click very loose.
The Neptune text spacing is far away from each other.
That's all for the activity.
I hope you learn more by exploring the planets in our solar system.
By using the basic font formatting, paragraphing formatting, and the different types of slides.