Lesson 2: The Clipboard and The Paragraph
Welcome back!
In this video, you will learn how to use the clipboard and the paragraph formatting tools.
First, let's talk about the clipboard.
This is the clipboard.
To copy and paste a text, simply
highlight a text and click the copy button.
Now, click on an area in your document
where you want to paste the text.
Click the paste button and there you have it.
To remove it, let’s use the cut button.
Let’s highlight the text again and then click cut. There you go, the text is now gone.
There you go, the text is now gone.
Let’s move on to the Paragraph formatting tools.
Let’s start with the lists.
This is the bulleted list button
The numbered list button
And multi-layered list button
Let’s click the bulleted list button.
Now, let’s type different kinds of grocery items.
flour, eggs, milk, bread, shampoo, soap, detergent
Excellent! We have a short grocery list.
This small circle is what you call a bullet.
If you want to change it, you can click on this button
and choose different bullet styles from the library.
How about this square one?
Let’s click it.
Do you see the difference?
Good.
Now let’s change it into a numbered list.
To do so, click this button.
Easy! Now you have a numbered grocery list.
Do you want a more organized list?
We can do that too!
Let’s organize our grocery items into two categories
Food and Toiletries
Type Food and click enter.
To add a layer, click Tab.
This automatically moves the next line a little
to the right and changes the bullet style.
Now, let’s type flour, eggs, milk, and bread.
Type Toiletries and click enter then Tab.
Now type, shampoo, soap, and detergent.
Very good!
Now we have an organized multi-layered grocery list.
These are the other Paragraph formatting tools.
This button will align your text to the right.
This button will align your text to the center.
This button will align your text to the left.
And this button will align your text evenly.
This button will change the space between your texts.
This is called spacing
And these numbers represent the
amount of space you want in your document.
This is what a 1.0 spacing looks like.
While this is what a 2.0 spacing looks like.
These are the indention buttons.
This will move your text away from the margin
and this will move it closer to the margin.
A margin is made up of invisible lines that
serve as a guide for the text in your document.
Now, let’s add a title for our grocery list.
Hmm, I want the title to look bigger but
I don’t want to use the font size button.
To do this, let’s look at Styles.
Click on this arrow down button to see more styles.
Let’s choose "Title" style for our title.
Excellent
Excellent! Now, the title is bigger and easier to read.
Good job for finishing Lesson 2.
In the next video, you will be learning
how to insert content in Microsoft Word.