LESSON 1: Introduction to Microsoft Excel
Hey there! Welcome to the Microsoft Excel Course.
In this video, you will learn the basics of Microsoft Excel.
First, let’s define Microsoft Excel.
Microsoft Excel is a spreadsheet computer
program that is used to record and analyze data.
Do you know what data is?
A data is any kind of
information, it can be in
the form of letters,
words, and even numbers.
Now let’s start by opening Microsoft
Excel and clicking on “Blank Workbook”.
Do you know what a workbook is?
A workbook is a collection of worksheets.
And a worksheet is a collection of rows and columns.
This is what a worksheet looks like.
Now, let’s go to the top-most part of your screen.
Do you see these three buttons?
This is the save button, it will let you
keep your work inside the computer.
You can also press the control button and S
button on your keyboard to save your work.
This is the undo button, it will remove your last action.
And this is the redo button, this is
like a reverse for your undo action.
Now, let’s go over to the right side.
These are the main control buttons.
This button will minimize your Excel
This button will make your Excel smaller or bigger.
And this button will take you out of Microsoft Excel.
So, make sure not to click it unless you’re done.
This is the toolbar.
The toolbar is made
up of many tabs and has
tools that can help you
in using Microsoft Excel.
Below the toolbar is your spreadsheet.
Can you see the tiny rectangles?
Those are called cells and cells will hold your data.
This right here is a Name box.
A name box will show you the cell name.
A cell name is made up of a Column Letter and a Row number.
These are the Column letters.
And these are the Row numbers.
This is a formula bar.
This is where you put formulas or insert data.
This is the leaf bar, it shows you which worksheet you’re working on.
In Excel, you can work with many worksheets.
These right here are the View buttons.
This is the normal view button, it will
make your Excel page look like this.
This is the page layout view button, it will make your Excel page look like this.
This is the page break view button, it will make your Excel page look like this.
This is the Zoom Control.
It will let you zoom in and out of your Excel page.
Drag this little rectangle to the right
to zoom in and to the left to zoom out.
Good job!
Now you know the basics of Microsoft Excel.