Lesson three.
Adding graphical elements to your presentation.
In this video you will be learning adding graphical elements to your presentation.
Objectives
Create basic theme designs and put some shapes
and learn transition effects for powerpoint presentation.
Topic A: Design and theme.
As you can see here this is the toolbar for the powerpoint.
Now look for to design button which is here.
Now click the design button
if you click the design button it will lead you to this interface.
Interface is what you see see on your screen.
So you can see here there's these two underlined words the theme and variant.
Then pick any design in the theme that you want to use for your powerpoint presentation.
Let us choose one example design in this theme.
Now we picked this one then let's pick variant that want for the theme that we choose.
We choose this variant here now this is what it looks like
but you can always choose any kind of design that you want for your powerpoint presentations like here in the design tool box.
Topic B: Insert shapes
Now let's move on to insert shape.
In the insert shape you can also find it in the powerpoint toolbar.
Just click insert in the upper left which is here.
Next click the shapes button which is here.
Once you click the shape button this will appear
Now you can choose any kind of shapes that you want to use for your powerpoint presentation slide.
Now let's pick rectangle.
After you click the rectangle shaped.
Long press the left mouse button
and drag so that the shape will appear.
Like this.
Next click this button here to pick a color for your selected shape.
After you click it the multiple color choices will appear.
Now let's pick a color.
We choose the color red for the chosen shape.
You can always pick any different kind of shape here in shapes button.
You can always decide what color you want for the shape.
That's it for inserting shapes for your powerpoint presentation slide.
Topic C: Transitions
Now let's move on to powerpoint transitions.
Transitions provide a simple way to move from one slide to the next during a slideshow.
Slideshows makes the powerpoint presentation looks entertaining.
Click the home button in the upper left corner of the powerpoint interface.
Here.
Once you've click it.
Click the new slide button
here.
Then this will appear.
You can select different kinds of slides here.
Now let's select tree sample slides here.
Now that we selected three slides from new slide button.
You can see it here in the left corner of the powerpoint interface.
Now that we already select slides.
Let's move on to the transition button which is here.
After you click the transition slide.
That transition tool box will appear like this.
Now you can select here which transition would you like to use for your slide.
The purpose of transitions in slide is for your powerpoint slide presentation to look appealing and amazing to watch.
Now let's select four different transitions for our four different slides
We choose the fade, push, wipe, and split transitions.
These stars here indicate that you already selected a transition for your slides.
Now click this button here in the upper left corner.
This is where you can see the transitional effects that you've chosen earlier.
Then in your keyboard look for the arrow button
Now click the right arrow button for you to be able to see the transitional effects you've chosen.
And that's it
Congratulations.
Now you know how to use graphical elements for your powerpoint presentation.
In the next video you will be learning about adding objects to your presentation.