Lesson 1: Introduction to Microsoft Word
Hi there!
Welcome to Lesson 1
In this video, we will be learning
the basics of Microsoft Word.
First, let’s define Microsoft Word
Microsoft Word is a computer program that
lets you create documents such as letters.
Let’s start by opening Microsoft
Word and clicking on “Blank document"
This is what you should see.
Let’s look at the left
top-most part of your screen.
This is the save button, it will keep
your document in your computer.
This is the undo button, it will
take away the last thing you did.
This is the redo button, it
will reverse an undo action.
Now, let’s move to the right
top-most part of your screen.
These are the main control buttons.
This button will minimize your Microsoft Word.
This button will make your
Microsoft Word smaller or bigger.
And this button will take you out of Microsoft Word.
So, don't click it yet, unless you are done!
This is the horizontal ruler.
And this is the vertical ruler.
Great!
Let’s try typing “Hello world” in
our document by using our keyboard.
This is what a keyboard looks like.
A keyboard has many letters, numbers, and symbols.
To type, simply press the buttons you need.
For this, we will need H-E-L-L-O W-O-R-L-D.
Great!
We just typed Hello World.
Let’s change the font style and font size.
A font is a set of letters, number and symbols.
To change the style, click here.
Let’s choose this font style.
To change the size, click here.
Let’s choose this size.
Now let’s type “Hello World” again.
Excellent! Do you see the difference?
Good.
There are also other different font
formatting tools in Microsoft Word.
This is the Bold format.
It will make your text look like this.
This is the Italicize format.
This is the Underline format,
It will make your text look like this.
This is the Strikethrough format.
These buttons right here will also change the font size.
This button will make your text bigger.
And this button will make your text smaller.
Now, let’s try typing “Hello world” with red letters.
To change the font color, click this.
Do you see the color red?
Perfect.
Let’s choose red.
Okay, let’s type “Hello world”.
That looks amazing!
There are also letter case formats
It will change your letters into small or big letters.
This is Sentence case, only the first letter is big.
This is Lowercase, all letters are small.
This is Uppercase, all letters are big.
This is Capitalize Each Word, all first letters of each word is big.
This is the Toggle case; it makes
small letters big, and big letters small.
Let’s move on to the highlight button
This button will highlight your text with colors.
Let’s try it. Click on highlight and choose a color.
Do you know how to highlight using your mouse?
Click the left button of your mouse and don’t let it go, drag it until all letters are highlighted in gray.
Once you let go, the highlight color will appear.
Excellent!
Good job!
Now you know the basics of Microsoft Word.