Lesson 4: Communicating Online
Objectives
Using emails, instant messaging and online chatting
Hi!
Welcome to the Internet Literacy course!
Today we’ll be learning how to use the Internet to communicate online!
Let’s start now, shall we?
The internet has made online communication easier than ever
suddenly
we have the power to chat, laugh, and connect
with people all over the world in seconds.
But you may be wondering
how can I make sure I'm being safe, effective, and
using the best available tools in the digital world?
There are a lot of ways to communicate
online such as using Gmail and Facebook
but let’s focus on Gmail for now.
Gmail is a free email service made by Google that
allows you to create and send emails to other people.
In order to access Gmail, let us first
open any web browser and go to google.com
Upon opening it
we can see on the top right-side
that it says G-mail, click on it
After that, we will be greeted by a new page
which allows us to create or sign in our account.
For starters, we should first create an account.
Upon clicking on create an account
we’ll see a form that prompts us to enter our first name,
last name, username, two forms for password to confirm it.
Upon clicking on confirm
next
we need to input our phone number
in it to proceed with the creation.
This is done in order to verify that
we are creating an account for our use.
After that, we’ll have to input
other additional information
such as our birthday and gender.
Once that is complete
Click on next and confirm your account creation.
After our account creation
We are going to be sent straight away to our
interface showing us the content of our email address.
On our gallery
we can see that we have primary
which is mostly the important emails
promotions which is usually business emails
Social which is social media emails such as
from Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and others.
In our left main menu
We can see that we have inbox which is what
automatically appears once we log in our account.
Next is starred which only displays emails that are important
Next is snoozed which are temporarily
removed emails from the Gmail interface
Next is sent which shows us our
sent emails towards other people
And drafts which contains our emails of
which are not yet sent and under construction
Let’s compose an email
lick compose on the top left which is located in the main menu!
Upon clicking on it
little menu appears which allows us
to write a message to someone else.
There are a lot of parts which we will explain
First is the to menu
which allows us to put the email of the
person we’re sending a mail to such as
Migasa_courseware@gmail.com
Second is the subject which is usually the main title of
heading of the mail dictating what the email is about!
Third is the content of the message which
we can insert the content of our message.
Upon closer look
on the center of the mail window,
there are a lot of different buttons.
The first button is called formatting option
which allows us to style our email with proper stylings.
The second button is called as attachment
which allows us to put files like pictures, music, videos and files in our email!
The third button, edit link
allows us to put a link to our email.
The fourth button, insert emoji
allows us to put icons to show specific feelings such as being happy or sad!
The fifth button, insert files from Drive
allows us to put files saved in a separate location that is stored online!
The sixth button, insert photo
allows us to put photos as content in our mails.
The seventh button, confidential mode
which makes us able to keep our
mails secure meaning the people who
receive it will not able to forward,
copy, print, or download this email.
The eight button, insert signature
which allows us to insert our signature to our emails.
The ninth button, more options
hich gives us options to make our experience much easier and
The last button, discard draft
which allows us to delete our created mail.
On the very left side, you will see a send button which
allows you to send your email as well as a little arrow
that gives you an option to send scheduled mails!
Now that you know how to send emails online
you can use this to send emails to other people and even chat with them
Remember, there is a need to maintain a responsible and proper online behavior and communication which we talked about in lesson