Lesson 2: Digital Citizenship
Objectives
Understanding the importance of being safe and
responsible while using the Internet
Ethical use of Technology
Good day!
Welcome to the Internet Literacy course!
Today we’ll be learning how to navigate
the worldwide Internet properly!
Let’s start, shall we?
See, the Internet is full of contents
videos, photos, texts, basically information which is created by a particular person or organization.
Using the Internet makes you connect with other thousand computers where you transfer information to each other
even personal details
Due to this, it’s important to understand how to be safe and responsible while on the Internet because your device could be in danger.
As we use the Internet, we enter something what is known as a ‘Digital Environment’.
A digital environment is simply more than just the Internet.
It is the interaction of connected digital contents such as Facebook, YouTube and others from commercial, public and other providers.
This includes the Internet, the World Wide Web,
mobile devices and networks, online apps
social media platforms, the media environment, online gaming
and any developments resulting in access to
or services needed to access the Internet.
With this
you need to follow basic guidelines upon
the use of the Internet in order to keep safe.
Keep it online
don’t give out personal contact
details like mobile phone number, home address
name of your school or
anything that gives away your location.
Keep it legal
be aware of the legal consequences of online activities.
This includes downloading music and films or harassing other people.
You are not anonymous online and things can get traced back to you
If you receive a rude or embarrassing image don’t pass it on
Distributing unconsented pictures/videos/internet properties by internet is harassment and could be illegal.
Keep in mind
not everyone you meet or see online is reliable.
Online contacts are strangers no matter how long you have been talking to them or how friendly they are
Never arrange to meet someone you have only talked to online without checking with a responsible adult.
Keep in control
If you meet someone online and conversations make you feel uncomfortable report it to the police or to an adult.
If you get messages which disturb or upset you
don’t reply and keep a record to report to an adult or your internet provider.
Keep your friends safe
Think before you send a picture or video and always ask permission from your friends
Once you have sent a picture you have lost control of it
Respect the privacy of your friends and don’t give out numbers or emails without their permission!
Keep alert
ccepting emails, instant messages or opening files from people you don’t know or trust can get you into trouble
They may contain viruses or unpleasant messages.
Keep it secure
Never give out your passwords.
Keep safe you have a right not to be harassed or bullied online. Make sure you tell someone if this happens to you.
Apart from this
there is also what they call ‘digital rights’
which makes it legal for people, like you, to create, use, access and publish content on the Internet
by using or accessing the computer.
Examples of this are copyrights, trademarks and patents.
A copyright means that a person owns a special right to something they made like a picture or a computer program
his means they get to decide
if others can copy it or not, like the MIGASA app.
A trademark is a special name, picture, or symbol that belongs to a certain company, group, or person.
It's like the MIGASA courseware logo, which only belongs to MIGASA
Last, but not least, patents.
A patent is when someone makes something new
and useful, like a machine or a recipe,
and they have the right to stop other people from
making, using, or selling it for a while.
It's like having a special secret that only you can use for a certain time.
You did well!
You’ve just finished learning the digital citizenship!
Next, we will learn about how to search information using search engines and finding information online easily!