Lesson 8: The Design Tab
Welcome to Lesson 8!
In this video, we will be learning about the Design Tab.
The Design Tab has many tools that will
make you document look nice and beautiful.
Let’s talk about Themes.
A theme in MS Word is a set of colors, fonts, and styles that
all work together to make your document look really nice.
Let’s click here to see the different Themes.
This is Document Formatting
It is also like a theme but it changes the way your document is formatted.
This is Colors, it has many color palettes
that can be used for Document Formatting.
A color palette is a set of different colors
Let’s click here to look at the different color palettes.
You can also change the Font styles
by clicking here and choosing a font style.
In the Design Tab, you can also add a watermark.
A watermark can be a text or
picture that is placed behind the text.
It is usually used to claim ownership.
Let’s click this to see the
different kinds of watermarks.
A watermark has a low opacity,
you can see it but not so much.
You can customize or change the text watermark
by clicking this and when the little box appears
You can start typing the text in this little box.
You can also change the font style, size and layout of the text.
To change the color of the whole page
We can click here and choose any color.
Let’s try this color.
Wow! Our page is now in the color of blue.
Now, let’s talk about Page Borders.
A page border is made up of lines all around the page.
It may look like a picture frame.
To change the page border, click here.
A little box will appear
And from there you can choose a border.
This little box gives you a preview
of what your page will look like.
You can also change the border
color here, just click and choose.
You can change the border
weight here, and the border art here.
Once you’re done, just click OK.
Very good!
Now you know how to use Themes, Watermarks, and Page Borders.
Hello there!
Now that you know how to use the tools
in the Design Tab and how to Mail Merge
Let’s try to make a certificate.
In this activity, we will be making an Award Certificate.
First, let’s click on the Layout Tab
And choose the Landscape Orientation.
Very good!
Then, let’s go to the Design Tab and
Click Page Borders to add a page border.
Let’s choose this border and click OK.
Perfect!
Now we have a border.
Next, let’s type our heading
Let’s click on the Home tab and choose Heading 1
Then click on the font size and choose 48.
Now, let’s click this alignment to center the text.
Now let’s type, C-O-N-G-R-A-T-U-L-A-T-I-O-N-S.
Very good!
We now have a Heading.
Let’s go back to the Design Tab and choose a Theme.
Click this and let’s choose this theme.
Perfect!
Now, let’s type the rest of the Certificate.
Just copy what I’m typing.
Very good!
We now have a certificate.
This certificate is for you!
Because you have done such an excellent job.
Let’s read it.
Congratulations!
You have been a very good student
You will receive 5 stars.
Now, let’s give certificates to other students.
Let’s go to the Mailings Tab and Select Recipients.
Let’s use the list from Lesson 7.
Now, let’s insert the merge fields by clicking this.
Click First Name and Last Name.
Now, let’s click Finish and Merge then click this to see our certificates.
There you go!
We now have 10 certificates with different recipients.
Excellent work!