Lessons four.
Adding objects your presentation.
In this video you will the learning adding objects your presentation.
Creating list for a paragraphs, aligning, ordering and grouping objects as well.
Objectives
Create basic list, indentions, line spacing, aligning, ordering
and grouping objects to your powerpoint presentation.
Topic A: List
As you can see here we have a sample presentation.
I'm going to teach you how to create the list
for the paragraphs or text you've been using for your presentation
But first let's highlight this group of text here.
To highlight the text.
You need to click and the hold the left mouse button and select group of text you wish to highlight.
Like this.
After highlighting the group of text.
Click this button here.
After clicking this button.
This bar will appear.
Now click this bullet and numbering here.
And this will appear.
The purpose of this bar is for you to customize the list you want the use for your group of text.
Now let's pick this one here.
Now let's choose some color here.
Click this icon here and pick any color you want to use but for now let's pick black.
Then click the ok button.
If you look at the side of your paragraph the dots will appear.
Now we're done using list for our text or paragraphs that we use for our presentation.
That's it for a list in power point presentation.
Topic B: Indents and Line spacing.
Indent and line spacing are two important features you can use to change the way text appear on the slide.
What is indents?
Indent or indention helps to format the layout of text so it appears more organized on your slide.
The fastest way to indent is to use the tab key.
Click on the space you want to indent.
For example here.
At the very beginning of the line.
Then press the tab key.
Look for the tab key in your keyboard
right here
Now your paragraph and look like this.
This space here is what we call indent for your paragraph to look organized.
This is what it looks like if all the paragraphs use the indention feature.
Next let's head for a paragraph spacing.
I will teach you how to use spacing and.
Now highlight the text or paragraph then click this.
You can choose which spacing for your text that you would like to use from one point zero to three point zero.
Now lets pick one point five.
And this is what it looks like.
Your paragraph looks more organized.
That's it for indent and line spacing.
Topic C: Aligning, Ordering and Grouping Objects.
Now let's move to aligning, ordering, and grouping objects.
Aligning objects.
The purpose of the aligning objects is for the objects or pictures to look more organized and not messy.
Now as you can see here the objects are not organized.
To make it look organized.
First look for the shift key on your keyboard.
which is here.
Now hold the shift key while clicking each object or pictures.
The object should look like this.
Next click the picture format in the toolbar
which is here.
Then click this button here.
And this will appear.
Now you can choose any alignment you wish to use.
Now let's try allign middle.
Now this is what that looks
more organized that's it for alligning objects for your presentation.
Now let's move to ordering objects.
The ordering is important when two or more objects overlap.
Because it will determine which objects are in the front or in the back.
When objects are added to a slide.
The levels of which they are place depend on the order in which they were added.
Although we've created the arrow in our example on the top level.
We can the just the level to place it beneath the the other items.
Now click shape format button.
Now click this.
And this will appear.
Click send to back.
Now this is how it looks like.
That's for the ordering objects in powerpoint presentation.
We’re almost done, hang in there!
Lastly grouping objects.
To confirm that multiple items stay together when they are moved or resized, you might want to group them into a single object.
Now let's try to group this objects or pictures.
Hold shift key in your keyboard then click each picture so it would look like this.
Now click the picture format button.
here.
Click this icon button here
and this will appear
Now click group.
And this is what it looks like
Congratulations.
Now you know how to add objects for presentation.
That's all for lessons four adding objects for your presentation.
In the next video you will learn about adding tables and charts to your presentation.
Activity for lessons four
Now that you know how to add objects your presentation.
Let's try this activity.
create a slide for kind of flower. first click new slide and pick picture with caption.
Next let’s type "Sunflower: for our example.
In the lower box, type what can you say about a sunflower.
Now let's highlight the text and click this here.
Now the text should look like this.
Last let’s put picture of Sunflower, to do that click this computer like icon here.
And this will appear.
Now click the picture.
Next click the insert button.
And this is what it should look like
that's it for activity about adding objects to your presentation.