LESSON 7: Excel Functions
Hi there! Are you ready to
learn about the Excel Functions?
So, in this video, we will be learning
how to do the different functions of Excel.
Excel Function is a
mathematical calculation
that is used to calculate
values in a spreadsheet
Let’s start with AVERAGE.
The Average function is used to
generate a number that represents
a typical value from a range,
distribution, or list of numbers.
For example, let's say you want to find the average of the following numbers
10, 15, 20, 25, and 30.
Now, click on the cell where
you want the average to appear.
And then after that type the formula
=AVERAGE (A1:A5) in the cell
“AVERAGE” is the function,
inside the parentheses are
the cell names A1 and A5
which are separated by a colon.
This formula tells Excel to find the
average of the values in cells A1 to A5.
Then press Enter to calculate the average.
Now, the result will appear in the cell you selected.
If you don’t want to type
the formula, you can also
highlight cells A1 to A5
and this little box will appear.
Click this and go to Totals, then click Average.
This will automatically show you the
average without typing in the formula.
MIN and MAX
Now, let’s move on to the MIN and MAX functions in Excel
The MIN function returns the smallest value in a range of cells.
While the MAX function returns the largest value.
Let's find out the smallest value among these numbers.
Let’s select this cell and type the formula
=MIN(A1:A5)
Again, we started with the equal sign,
the function, and then the cell names.
Now, let’s press Enter on the keyboard.
Excellent!
You can now see the smallest value.
Now let’s find out the largest value.
To do so, click on this cell and type the formula
=MAX(A1:A5)
then press Enter
Good job!
Next, let’s work on how to add the
Date & Time in Excel automatically.
To do so, just click on any cell and type the formula
=NOW()
then press Enter
There you go!
The time and date is now
displayed and this will update
automatically every time
you open the Excel file.
Next, we will talk about the COUNT function.
This function will count the
number of cells that have numbers.
This will not work on cells with text.
Let’s look at this table.
Many of these cells have
numbers but some have text, instead
of counting them one by one,
let’s use the COUNT function.
Let’s select this cell and type in the formula
=COUNT(A1:A20)
then click enter
There you have it
we can now see the number
of cells with numerical values
Now, let’s move on to the “IF” Function
The IF function is one of the most commonly used functions in Excel.
It allows you to test a condition
and return one value if the
condition is true, and other
value if the condition is false.
Does it sound complicated?
Well, just imagine this scenario.
A raincoat is only used when it is raining outside right?
IF it is raining
then you will wear a raincoat
IF it is not raining
then you will not wear a raincoat
Now are you ready to use the IF function?
Great! Let’s try the rain scenario first.
You can see that in A1, the data is “Raining”.
While in A2, the data is “Not Raining”.
In column B, let’s try to find out if
we should wear a raincoat or not.
In cell B1, type the formula
=IF(A1=”Raining”, “Yes”, “No”)
If A1 is equal to Raining then the word Yes will be displayed
if not then No will be displayed.
Now, let's press Enter.
There you go! Yes is displayed
because A1 is equal to raining.
Now, let’s talk about CONDITIONAL FUNCTIONS.
Let’s talk about the conditional function, SUMIF.
Let’s look at this table and find
out the total sum of all the Carrots.
To do so, select this cell and type in this formula
=SUMIF(A1:A10, “Carrot”, B1:B10)
This is the function, this is the range of
cells where you want to find carrots, this is
the criteria which is the word “Carrot” and
this is the range of cells that you will sum up.
Now, let’s click enter and see the total sum of all the Carrots.
Very good!
Now, let's talk about the
conditional function,  COUNTIF.
Let’s try to find out the count of Broccolis.
To do so, type this formula
This formula will find
all the broccolis and
count how many there
are in cells A1 to A10.
Finally, we have the conditional function, AVERAGEIF.
Let’s try to find out the average price of Eggplant.
To do so, type this formula
=AVERAGEIF(A1:A10, "Eggplant",   B1:B10)
This formula will add all the prices of the Eggplants
you can find in B1 to B10 and then divide it by
the number of Eggplants you can find in A1 to A10 and
then finally reveal the average price of Eggplant.
Excellent work!
Now you know the different functions in Microsoft Excel.
In the next video, you will be making a
simple budget system for a Lemonade Stand.