Lesson 5: Layout
Are you ready to learn?
In this video, we are going to talk about Microsoft Word Layout.
A layout is how a certain thing is arranged.
In Microsoft Word, you can adjust the page layout.
Here are the tools that will help you change the page layout.
First, let’s talk about Margins.
A margin is made up of horizontal and vertical
lines that serve as an invisible guide
A margin may look like this, but you can’t really see it.
Microsoft Word has different kinds
of margins. Let’s click here to find out.
Changing the margin will change the
way your text looks like in the document.
Let’s try choosing this margin.
Do you see the difference?
You can also click on Custom
Margins to customize your own margin
You can adjust the
numbers to go higher or lower.
Next, we have the Orientation.
A page orientation is how the page is laid out.
There are two types, landscape orientation and portrait orientation.
Let’s try changing the orientation to landscape.
There you go!
The page has become wider.
Let’s bring it back to portrait.
Can you see the difference?
Let’s move on to the size.
A document can be in many sizes.
Let’s click here to find out the sizes.
The most common sizes are A4 and Letter.
Let’s try clicking on this page size.
Can you see the difference?
The page has become longer.
Now, let’s talk about columns.
A column is a vertical division of text.
This is a column.
This is also a column.
There are two columns.
Let’s click here and change it to three columns.
Great! We now have three columns.
Congratulations!
Now you know how to use Page Layout in Microsoft Word.