Lesson 9: The Review and View Tab
Hi there!
In this video, we will be learning about the Review Tab and View Tab.
The Review Tab has many tools that can help
you correct mistakes or finalize your document.
The View Tab has many tools that can help
you control the way you view your document.
First, let’s talk about Spelling and Grammar.
If you click this, a little box will pop up
And let you know the grammatical or spelling errors in your document.
Over here is the Thesaurus.
A thesaurus is like a magic dictionary that
helps you find similar words or synonyms.
To find out the synonym of a word, click the
Thesaurus and this little box will pop up.
Type the word here and click this little search button.
All the synonyms or the words similar
to the word you typed will appear here.
This is the Word Count
It counts all the words, pages, characters
and paragraphs that are in your document.
Just click it and this little box will appear
Then you will see the number of
pages, words, characters and many more.
You can also see the number of words and
pages on the bottom left part of your screen.
Now, let’s proceed to the View tab.
This is Read Mode, and this is what it will do to your document.
It makes it easier for you to read the
texts but you won’t be able to edit it.
This is Print Layout or the default view.
This is how it looks and it
lets you edit your document.
This is Web Layout, it lets you
view your document like this.
This is Outline view
Your document will look like a bulleted
list.
To exit, just click Close Outline View.
And lastly, this is the Draft view
It looks similar to the Web Layout.
You can also change the Views by clicking on these
buttons on the right bottom part of your screen.
This is the Read Layout, Print Layout, and Web Layout.
You can also change the page movement.
This is the vertical page movement
It goes up and down if you use
the scroll bar which is right here.
This is the side-to-side page movement
If you click it, your document
will look like this and you
can move it from side to
side using the scroll bar below.
Remember the ruler?
You can check this to make the ruler appear.
And you can check this to make the gridlines appear.
The ruler and gridlines can be a guide for your document.
And this is the Navigation Pane, it will
let you find words in your document easily.
These right here are the Zoom options.
You click Zoom and choose the Zoom
percentage or type it in this little box.
Click OK and you will be Zoomed in or Zoomed out.
You can also adjust the Zoom
by using this Zoom control bar.
Just drag this little rectangle
to the right to move closer to
the document and to the left to
move far away from the document.
If you want to look at one page at a time, just click this.
If you want to look at many pages at a time, just click this.
But if you want to zoom in on a page easily, just click this.
Good job!
Now you know how to control your
Document View in Microsoft Word.