Lesson 5: Tables and Drop-downs
Hey there!
In this video, we will be learning
about tables and drop-downs.
Do you know what a table is?
A table is made up of rows and columns
and will help you arrange your data!
You can find the table button in the Insert tab of Microsoft Excel.
It looks like this.
Now, let’s try making a table.
Here we have a list of
grocery items and their price.
Let’s highlight all the cells with data
then let’s go to the Insert tab
and click on the Table button.
Once this little box pops up
let’s check this little box and then click OK
There you go! We now have a table.
Would you like to make
our table look awesome?
Great!
Let’s change its color and style.
Go to the Table Design tab and
choose a table design from here.
Let’s choose this!
Wow! Our table looks nicer!
Now let’s talk about
this little arrow down
button that is seen in
every header of our table.
This button reveals all the sorting and filtering options.
Remember sort and filter from Lesson 3?
That’s right!
We can sort and filter each
column in our table automatically.
To insert a new row or column
go to the Home tab and click this button right here.
You can now insert a row above or below.
And you can also insert
columns to the right or to the left.
Now let’s calculate all the prices and find out the total price.
Do you think we should use the SUM formula?
Nope! We don’t have to!
Once you have a table in
Excel, you can find out the total by
simply going to the Table Design
tab and checking the Total Row box.
When you click it, the total row will
appear at the bottom of your table.
Amazing isn’t it?
Now let’s talk about drop-downs!
Sometimes when you make a table you need to
enter the same 3 or more data repeatedly.
Making drop-downs will make that job easier!
Let’s go back to the table we made earlier,
but this time I added a group column.
But it's empty, so let’s assign
these items to their groups.
Toothbrush, soap, and shampoo all go to the Toiletries group.
Banana, milk, and bread all go to the Food group.
Now to categorize each item
easily, let’s make a drop-down.
To do so, let’s select
all the cells under
the group column and
then go to the Data Tab.
Click on the Data Validation button.
Now, click this little button and choose List.
In the source box right here, we type in Toiletries, comma, Food.
Make sure that the two groups
are separated with a comma.
Then, we click OK.
Now let’s click on this cell.
Do you see the drop-down button?
Good! Let’s click it and choose the group for this item.
Toothbrush belongs to the Toiletries group.
Banana belongs to the Food group.
Finish the rest and this is what it should look like
Excellent!
Now we can easily group these
items using the drop-down menu!
Good job!
Now you know how to create tables
and drop-downs in Microsoft Excel.