Lesson 7: Mail Merge
Welcome to Lesson 7!
In this video, we will be learning about Mail Merge.
Mail Merge will help you create a lot of
letters, invitations, certificates and many more.
Have you ever tried writing a letter?
A letter usually has a Salutation or a
Greeting, the body, and the Signature.
In the Salutation, we usually put the name of the recipient.
A recipient is the person that is going to receive the letter.
We need to make 10 letters.
But instead of typing different
names in the salutation for many times
We can just use mail merge.
Let’s click here and choose letter.
Now, let’s click Select Recipients.
You can add a new list or use an existing list.
For this tutorial, we will use an existing list.
Let’s click here and choose this file.
Now, our recipient list has
been added to the document.
Let’s click the Edit Recipient List
to see the names of our Recipients.
As you can see, we have their
Last Name, First Name, and Title.
Click OK and let’s start the mail merge.
To add their Last Name, First Name, and Title
to the salutation click Insert Merge Field.
Just click Title, First Name, and Last Name.
Now, just click Finish and Merge
Then let’s click this so we
can see and edit our letters.
Amazing!
We now have 10 letters with different recipients.
Excellent work!
Now you know how to use the Mail Merge.