Lesson 6: Charts
Welcome to Lesson 6!
In this lesson, we will be learning about charts!
What is a chart?
A chart is a visual representation
of data from a spreadsheet
that can help us to understand
the information more easily.
To make our chart, let’s go back
to the table we made from Lesson 5.
In this table we have
the Item, Group and Price.
Now let’s do a little magic
and add the total sales of each
product from the months of
January, February and March.
Wow! We sold a lot of items!
Let’s try to find out which group sold
the most during the month of March.
To do so, let’s click on this cell here and press the control button and the letter Q on the keyboard.
Now this little box will pop up.
This is called quick analysis.
Now, let’s click on charts.
You will see more than one Clustered chart
click the first one.
Great!
Now we have a clustered
chart where we can see
what group sold the most
during the month of March.
Creating a chart will also add a
new worksheet to your workbook.
You can also make other
kinds of charts by going to
the Insert tab and choosing
from these kinds of charts.
We have
column charts
line charts
pie charts
hierarchy charts
statistical charts
scatter charts
stock charts
and even combo charts
Good job!
Now, you know how to create charts.