Lesson 3: Sort and Filter
Hey there, today we are going to
learn about Sorting and Filtering!
You can find the Sort and Filter
under the Home Tab, right here.
Sorting is like when you put all of your
toys in order from biggest to smallest.
In Excel, you can sort your data the same way!
You can choose to sort by numbers, letters, colors, dates or anything else you want.
In this column we have 5 different toys.
We have a dollhouse, a ball, an airplane toy, an elephant and a car toy.
Let’s sort these toys from A
to E based on the first letter.
Highlight all these cells, then let’s go ahead and click Sort and Filter.
Click Sort A to Z.
Perfect!
Now our toys are sorted from A to E.
Now, let’s talk about Filter.
In Excel, a filter is like a
magic tool that helps you find
and see only the information
you want from a big list or table.
Let’s go ahead and look at our sorted list of toys again.
Let’s highlight all of it and click
on Sort and Filter then click Filter.
Now, you will see a little arrow down button here.
Let’s click it and find out how to filter.
Let’s click Text Filter and choose Begins with.
This filter will only show text that begins with a certain letter.
Let’s type A here and click OK.
There you go!
Only the Airplane toy can be seen because
its the only toy that begins with letter A!
Excellent Work! Now you know how to sort and filter data in Microsoft Excel. In the next video, you will learn about basic arithmetic operations in Excel.
Now you know how to sort
and filter data in Microsoft Excel.