Lesson one.
Getting started with powerpoint
Hi there.
In this video you will be learning about powerpoint environment.
Objectives.
Navigate the powerpoint environment view and navigate the presentation
create and save a powerpoint presentation.
So first
What this Microsoft powerpoint?
Microsoft powerpoint is a computer program that will help you to make a cool presentation like slide shows.
And in this course we will teach you how to make one.
Let's start by opening your Microsoft powerpoint.
Clicked the blank presentation to create a presentation.
Can you see this?
Those are at templates.
Templates as her like ready made design that we can use for our presentation to make it pretty.
After clicking the blank presentation
This is what you'll see.
First we'll talk about what you can see in the screen.
This is called a slide.
This is where you can edit and add words.
On the left side of the screen is a small version of the slide and you can also see numbers of slides that you have.
And the lower right part of the screen are the zoom in and zoom out buttons.
Just slide left or click the minus button to zoom out
and slide right or click the plus button to zoom in.
This button will make your slide the arrange itself.
This button will maximize the slide presentation.
This button will allow all the slide to be in order.
This button will change your view to read mode.
And lastly this button will change your slide to normal.
If you look at the upper right of your screen you can see this buttons.
This will make your Microsoft farpoint go smaller.
This about that makes your Microsoft powerpoint go bigger.
This button makes you exit your Microsoft powerpoint.
Now if you look up the upper left corner of the screen you will see this buttons.
This button will help you access certain buttons immediately.
This button will maximize the slide presentation.
This button and will remake your previous action.
This button will undo your action.
This button will save your project.
Great start
now let us make a simple presentation.
First click the box that says "Click the add title"
After clicking it type "Lesson 1"
Now that we're finished making our presentation it's time to save it.
Will go to file
and select save us.
Select the desktop
the name your presentation as "Lesson 1"
Congratulations
Now you're familiar with the environment of the Microsoft powerpoint.
And the next lesson you will learn about developing a powerpoint.