Lesson 4: Header, Footer, and Symbols
Hello there!
In this video, we will be learning
about Header, Footer and Symbols.
This is where you will
find the Header and the Footer.
A header is placed on top of the page.
A footer is placed on the bottom of the page.
To add a header, click on this button
and you will see header templates.
Templates are ready-to-use
and will make things easier for you.
To add a footer, click on this button and you will see footer templates.
You can also double click on the
top part of the page
To insert a header and start typing just like this.
You can do the same to insert a
footer and start typing just like this.
You may also add a page number.
A page number can be placed in the header or footer.
To add a page number, click on this button and you will see Page number templates.
Let’s choose this.
Can you see the page numbers on the pages?
Microsoft Word automatically counts the pages and places
a page number in each page with just a few clicks.
From here, you can also insert a textbox and word art.
Since we already talked about how
to add a textbox in the previous lesson
We will only try word art this time.
To add a word art, click this button.
Can you see the beautiful word art?
There are many and you can choose
anything to make your text look nice.
Let’s try by clicking on this word art.
Once this box appears, we can start typing inside it.
Perfect!
We now have beautiful word art.
Let’s move on to Symbols.
A symbol is a representation of anything.
These are examples of symbols.
To insert a symbol, simply click on this button
and choose from the different kinds of symbols.
A symbol can also be used in equations.
An equation is like a mathematical sentence, it
uses symbols like plus, minus, times and many more.
To insert an equation, click this button.
Once you click it, all these symbols and equations will
appear together with a small box that looks like this.
This is the equation box, this is where you will put your equation
Let’s try creating an equation of 2 times ½.
To do so, click on the equation box and type 2.
Then, click on the multiplication symbol.
After that, click on the fraction
equation and choose this fraction.
The top part is for the numerator and
the bottom part is for the denominator.
Our numerator is 1 and our denominator is 2.
Very good! We now have an equation.
Congratulations!
Now you know how to insert a header, footer and symbol.