Hey there! It’s activity time!
You are almost done with the Microsoft Excel Course
you just have one more thing to do.
In this activity we will be making a Simple
Budget System for Rosa’s Lemonade Stand.
First, let’s open Microsoft Excel
and create a new workbook.
Let’s make a table for Expenses
first. Add In the headers;
“Item”, “Quantity”, “Unit Cost”
and “Total Cost” in Row 1.
Then under Item, let’s list Lemons, Sugar, Cups and Ice.
Under Quantity, let’s list 100, 200, 150, 60.
And under Unit Cost, let’s list; 2,3,1,5.
Let’s highlight these cells, go to the Insert tab and click table.
Check this little box then click OK.
Now we have a table. But
we need to find out the total
cost! Let’s click on this
cell and type in the formula
=B2*C2
Drag the cross down to copy the formula to the other cells and there you go!
Very good!
To calculate the total expenses,
let’s type “Total Expenses”
in this cell and click on this
cell then type this formula
=SUM(D2:D5)
The Total Expenses can now be seen in the worksheet.
Next, we have to make another table.
This is what we call the Sales table.
Hop on to the 8th row and add in the headers
“Item”, “Quantity”, “Unit Cost” and “Total Cost”
Then under Item, we will list the different
kinds of Lemonades Rosa is selling.
Let’s add in, “Regular” “Pink” and “Blue”.
Very good!
Let’s take this chance to turn this into a table.
Simply highlight these cells, go to Insert and then click the table.
Now, let’s continue adding the Quantities of each item.
Rosa sold 50 regular lemonades, 40
pink lemonades, and 53 blue lemonades.
Under Unit Cost let’s type in the price of each lemonade.
Regular costs 35, pink and blue costs 40.
Very good!
Now, let’s calculate the total cost.
To do so, click on cell D9 and type this formula
=B9*C9
Drag the little cross down to copy the formula to other cells.
Excellent!
To calculate the total sales,
let’s type “Total Sales” in
this cell and click on this
cell then type this formula
=SUM(D9:D11)
Wow! Rosa earned a lot from her lemonade stand!
Now, let’s see how much her profit is.
To do so, let’s type “Profit” in this cell then type this formula in this cell
=D12-D6
We subtracted the total expenses from the
total sales to see Rosa’s overall profit.
Did Rosa profit from her business or lost?
To find out, let’s click on this cell and type this formula
=IF (D13>D6, "PROFIT", "LOSS")
This means that if her total sales
is greater than her total expenses,
then Rosa earned PROFIT. But
if not, then Rosa earned a LOSS.
Now, let’s click enter.
Hooray! Rosa earned PROFIT.
Excellent work!
You helped Rosa manage
her small business and
you also learned how
to use Microsoft Excel.
Congratulations on making it this far!