Lesson 6: References
Welcome to Lesson 6!
In this video, we will be
learning about the References tab.
This is the references tab
It has many tools that can help you.
First, let’s talk about how to insert a Table of Contents.
A table of contents is like a map for
all the content that is in our document.
It makes it easier for us to find what we are looking for.
To add a table of contents, let’s
click this button and choose a template.
Now you have an empty table of contents.
To update this, make sure that all the titles that you want to be
in this table of contents must be using the Headings 1 text style.
What do I mean by that?
Let’s go ahead and look at this book.
This book has 3 chapters.
It has chapters 1, 2, 3.
To include chapter 1 in the table of contents
Let’s highlight “Chapter 1” and click Headings 1.
Now, let’s go back to the table of
contents and click the update table.
There you go
Chapter 1 and its page number can
now be seen in the table of contents.
Repeat the process until all
chapters are in the table of contents.
Next, we are going to talk
about the Footnote and Endnote.
Footnotes are like secret messages at the bottom of the page
They help explain things and make your writing even better.
Endnotes are like secret messages at the end of the whole writing.
They're just like hidden treasures waiting for you to discover!
To add a footnote or endnote,
just click where you want to add it.
Choose either "Insert Footnote" or "Insert Endnote".
Then write your secret message!
Let’s click Insert Footnote and type “Hello world”.
It's super easy, right?
Let’s move on to the Citations and Bibliography
A citation is giving credit to the authors
that wrote the book you based your ideas from.
It usually follows an APA format and displays the author’s name and the year the book was published.
To add a citation, click the Insert Citation button and click Add New Source
You can choose the type of source, it can
be a book, journal, article and many more.
Now, let’s type in the Author’s name, the Title
of the book, the Year, City and Publisher.
As you can see the proper
citation is now in your document.
Now, let’s talk about the Bibliography.
A Bibliography also gives credit to the authors.
But it displays the author’s name, the year,
title, and place where the book was published.
Since we already have put the book information earlier
All we have to do now is click on the Bibliography button and then choose from any of these templates.
Excellent work!
Now you know all about the References Tab.