LESSON 4: Basic Arithmetic Operations
Hi! Welcome to Lesson 4.
In this video, you
will be learning about
basic arithmetic operations
in Microsoft Excel.
Do you know what an arithmetic operation is?
An arithmetic operation is
a mathematical operation.
In this video, we will be using Addition,
Subtraction, Division and Multiplication.
First, let’s talk about Addition.
Addition is adding or combining two or more numbers.
1+1 is equal to?
That’s right!
It is equal to TWO.
We can do addition using our
hands, our minds, and a calculator.
But we can also do it on Microsoft Excel.
So let’s try it.
Let’s put the first number inside cell A1
and the second number inside cell B1
It should look like this.
Now, click on cell C1 and add the
Addition formula in the formula box.
In every calculation in Excel, you
must always start with the equal sign.
Now, let’s add the Cell names.
Let’s put A1, the plus sign, and B1.
Click enter and as you can see the C1 cell
now has the sum of A1 cell and B1 cell.
Next, let’s try Subtraction.
Subtraction is taking away one number from another.
10-1 is equal to?
Very good!
It is equals to NINE.
Let’s try doing it in Excel.
First, let’s put 10 in A1 and 1 in B1.
Click on C1 and let’s add
the formula in the formula box.
Don’t forget to put the equal sign.
A1, the subtraction sign, and B1.
Let’s click enter.
Wow! Now we have the difference of 10 and 1.
Next, let’s try Multiplication.
Multiplication is when you take one number
and add it together a number of times.
For example, 5 multiplied by 4 is done like this
5+5+5+5.
We add 5 by itself four times.
And that is equal to?
Excellent! It is equal to 20.
Let’s do it in Excel.
Let’s put 5 in A1 and 4 in B1.
Click C1 and add this in the formula box
equal sign, A1, the asterisk sign, and B1.
Then, click enter.
There you go!
We now have the product of 5 and 4.
Lastly, we have Division.
Division is breaking a number
up into an equal number of parts.
If we divide 20 by 4
what do you think is the answer?
Let’s do it like this.
Imagine you have 20 balls and 4 boxes.
Now, let’s put these balls inside the 4 boxes.
Make sure that each box has the same number of balls.
How many balls are in one box?
Correct!
Each box has five balls.
And that is how you do division.
Let’s try it in Excel.
Put 20 in A1 and 4 in B1.
Click on C1 and add this formula
equal sign, A1, slash sign, and B1.
Then click enter.
There you go!
We now have the quotient of 20 and 4.
Wow you did so well!
In the next video, you will be
learning how to create tables!