LESSON 2: Cell Formatting
Welcome to Lesson 2!
In this video, you will learn how
to format a cell in Microsoft Excel.
This is a cell, all these rectangles are cells!
You can manually fill a cell by typing inside it.
You can also click a cell and type in its formula box.
But sometimes, you need to fill in lots of cells and that can take a long time.
That's where the Fill Handle comes in!
The Fill Handle can help you fill in lots of cells at once.
You can either copy a cell to other
cells or copy a pattern to other cells.
Let’s try copying “Hello” to the other cells below it.
To do so, drag this little cross down.
There you go!
Now, let’s try filling 10 cells in
Column A with numbers 1 to 10.
To do so, we must manually fill in the numbers 1 and 2.
Then, we can highlight both cells, drag the
little cross down until we reach cell A10.
Excel will automatically fill in the cells
with the same pattern as the original cell.
But remember that you
must manually fill in the first
two cells so that Excel
will understand the pattern.
Now, let’s talk about Split.
You can use Split to separate words
or numbers that are together in one cell.
Here's how you do it.
We have Jane Doe in cell A1
to separate Jane and Doe into two other cells
let's select this cell and go to the
Data Tab and click on Text to Columns.
A little box will pop up
choose Delimited and then click Next
After that, you will be asked to choose a delimiter.
The data inside a cell can be separated
with tab, semicolon, comma or space.
Since our data in
A1 is separated with a
comma, let’s choose
comma and then click next.
Now, let’s click on Finish.
There you have it!
Jane and Doe are now split into different cells.
Now, let’s proceed to Transpose.
Transpose in Excel is a
function that lets you flip or rotate
the range of cells from rows
to columns, or columns to rows.
We are gonna teach you the fastest
and easiest way to transpose data in Excel.
Let’s look at this schedule.
It has 4 columns and 2 rows.
Highlight all of it and clicking
copy from the clipboard.
Let’s now select 2 columns and 4 rows over here.
Then we click the right button of our mouse
and you can see the paste options here.
Let’s click this Transpose paste button.
Very good!
You have successfully transposed data in Excel.
Excellent work!
Now you know how to fill, split and
transpose cells in Microsoft Excel!