Lesson 1 Understanding the Internet
Objectives
Understanding the Internet
Knowing the Definition and Purpose of the Internet
Defining Basic Components and Structure of the Internet
Hello! Welcome to the Internet Literacy course!
Today we’ll be learning
how to be to be more cultured
and educated in using the
Internet in our everyday life.
Let’s start, shall we?
The Internet is a network of connection where millions of computers are connected to one another
which allows them to get information from other places
talk to other people from other places
watch videos and very much more.
Network, additionally, is just simply a connection between two or more computers that can share information.
Both were the greatest
inventions in the nineteen hundred
which changed lives of people forever
thus, making it easier than before.
Take a look around you!
Phones can now connect to the Internet as well as some televisions!
You can call a loved one million of miles away
watch a video on YouTube
play games online and even watch this course!
See
the Internet was made to quickly find information
provide communication
listen to music
watch videos
shop from your cellphone or computer
and other many reasons.
But wait
how does the Internet work?
Data or information moves over the Internet in an ability
which is called as ‘packet switching’.
Let’s say you want to send a message through Facebook’s Messenger
packet switching turns your simple ‘hello’
to someone else into tiny and separate pieces
before building it up normally again once
it reaches  the person you’re talking with.
Packet switching allows many people to use the Internet at the same time.
There are basic components that makes us able to use the Internet.
First is the client which is usually you
who is accessing the Internet.
As you access it
you are requesting data from a given server!
Server, on the other hand
responds to your request and provides you information.
The client and server communicate with protocols!
Protocols are a set of rules that help client
and server meet with one another.
They make sure that the data request is sent and received properly.
There are two protocols that every device has which are
Transmission Control Protocol or TCP
and the Internet Protocol or IP
which every device such as cellphones,
laptops, computers, smart TVs and other have!
What both of these protocols do, is that
the Internet Protocol, or IP
makes sure data on
the internet gets to the right place.
Then TCP or Transmission Control Protocol
makes sure the data is put in the right order,
and none of it is missing.
TCP also helps to control traffic on the
internet so it does not get overloaded.
These internet components enable us to search information, watch videos and others within minutes.
How do we access the Internet then?
In order to access the Internet, we use what they call as a web browser.
A web browser is an application or program that allows us to look and interact with the information on the Internet
such as Browser, Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox,
Microsoft Edge, Opera and many others.
Before accessing the Internet
make sure your device is connected
to a working network connection.
After that, on your desktop
find a Google Chrome logo which looks like this
double click on it
and there we go, you have just accessed the Internet.
Upon the usage of a web browser, we are presented with Online Content which are simply the things that you see on the Internet.
Ranging from videos, images, information, messages and others are all examples of online content.
Good Job!
You’ve just finished learning the basics of the Internet!
Next, we will learn about navigating the Internet in a safe and responsible manner in order to use it actively and respectfully!